<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Whoopee</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.ee</link>
  <description>Explore the power and versatility of Lua programming language. From beginner tutorials to advanced techniques. From beginner tutorials to advanced techniques, dive into Lua's elegant syntax and discover its applications in game development, scripting, embedded software and more. Also some useful stuff for web-development.</description>

  <item>
  <title>Graph</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/graph.html</link>
  <description>Definitive guide and implementation of the graphs in Lua language. Graph is one of the most important data structures, used in different kinds of advanced algorithms, like pathfinding, detecting cycles, logistics, maps, etc. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Priority queue</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/priority-queue.html</link>
  <description>Implementation of the priority queue in Lua. Priority queue is an abstract data type similar to queue and stack. The difference is that each element has a priority value. Values with higher priority are pulled first. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:08:43 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Variety of linked lists</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/variety-of-linked-lists.html</link>
  <description>Linked list is a classical data structure that can be used as data storage for different algorithms and efficient data management. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tuple</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/tuple.html</link>
  <description>Tuple is a data structure where values are ordered and unchangeable. In Lua, tuples are implemented as tables. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Set</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/set.html</link>
  <description>Set is a data structure with a collection of values where the value in the set may only occur once; it is unique in the set's collection. Check set implementation in Lua. -</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:08:08 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Circular doubly linked list</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/circular-doubly-linked-list.html</link>
  <description>Circular doubly linked list is a data structure that is a combination of both circular singly linked list and doubly linked list. It stores 2 pointers, one is pointing to the next node, the other to the previous node and the first pointer points to the last and correspondingly last to the first. This approach makes a continual circular loop. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Doubly linked list</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/doubly-linked-list.html</link>
  <description>Doubly linked list is a data structure similar to a singly linked list. With one significant difference: it stores 2 pointers, one is pointing to the next node, the other to the previous node. Check implementation of doubly linked list in Lua programming language. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Circular linked list</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/circular-linked-list.html</link>
  <description>A cicrular linked list is a data structure similar to linear singly linked list for storing and managing collections of data. All nodes are linked in a continuous circle. Circular linked list implementation in Lua. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 22:49:14 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Linked list</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/linked-list.html</link>
  <description>A linked list is a fundamental data structure in computer science used for storing and managing collections of data. Linked list implementation in Lua. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:08:02 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>List</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/list.html</link>
  <description>List abstract data structure in Lua language. Implementation of append, prepend, contains and find methods. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:07:45 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deque or double-ended queue</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/deque-or-double-ended-queue.html</link>
  <description>Deque or double-ended queue abstract data structure in Lua language. Implementation of push front, push back, pop front and pop back methods. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:07:29 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Queue</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/queue.html</link>
  <description>Queue abstract data structure in Lua language. Implementation of enqueue, dequeue, isEmpty, front and rear methods. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:07:18 +0300</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stack</title>
  <link>https://www.whoop.eepost/stack.html</link>
  <description>Stack abstract data structure in Lua language. Implementation of push, pop and isEmpty methods. </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:06:59 +0300</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
